# Hi, my name is Niklas Noldin.

I'm a *designer* and *creative coder* from the Austrian alps. I live in *Barcelona*, *Spain* and I'm available to work. Following my education in both *design and IT*, I spent many years developing *web apps on a global scale*. Now, I aim to apply my know-how in both fields creatively.

# **Experience**

# Sam Digital Head of Development

I co-founded <u>sam-digital.com</u> which helps companies in the metal industry to manage their coolant household. January 2021 – present

Remote

### Return on Art Chief Technology Officer

March 2023 - September 2023

#### **Educational leave**

March 2022 - February 2023

#### **Frontend Engineer**

October 2020 - February 2022

Vienna, Austria

### Taronja Escuela de Español Fullstack Engineer Mobile and Event Coordinator

August - December 2019

Valencia, Spain

### Atelier Christian Mariacher Graphic Design Internship

July – August 2016 and July – August 2015

Innsbruck, Austria

## Circus – Büro für Gestaltung Graphic Design Internship

July - August 2014

Innsbruck, Austria

# **Skills**

#### Creative

TouchDesigner, Resolume Arena, Cinema 4D, Cavalry, Figma, Final Cut Pro, Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

#### **Technologic**

JavaScript, CSS, Web Animation, Vue.js, Processing/p5.js, d3.js, PHP, Laravel, SQL

#### **Soft Skills**

Problem Solving, Product Development, Entrepreneurial Thinking

# **Education**

## HTL Construction and Design Specialized High School Degree in Graphic Design

September 2012 – June 2017

Innsbruck, Austria

# University of Applied Science Salzburg

BSc. in Multimedia Technology with a Major in Web Development

October 2017 - September 2020

Salzburg, Austria

## **University of Applied Arts Vienna**

**Educational Leave** 

Arts & Science, Stage Design, Exhibition Project Management September 2022 – February 2023

Vienna, Austria

## **University of Technology Vienna**

**Educational Leave** 

Data Visualization, User Experience Design

February - July 2022

Vienna, Austria

# Volunteer Work

#### **Junge Talstation Event Venue**

Member of the organization who runs an event venue inside an abandoned cable car station.

Design, Event Marketing, Social Media, Renovation, Bar Keeping, Projectionist Innsbruck, Austria

# Languages

German Native (C2) English Advanced (C1) Spanish Elementary (A2) Catalan Beginner (A1)



## hello@niklasnold.in +43 664 14 59 315 www.niklasnold.in Carrer de les Carretes 6/3/2 08001, Barcelona, Spain Date of Birth: 16.10.1997 Nationality: Austrian, Italian NIE: Z-0895256-D

Class B Driver's License

#### **Social**

linkedin.com/in/niklasnoldin instagram.com/nippiofficial